Guide to the Eleanor Lansing Dulles papers, 1867-1993 MS2217
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Employment, 05/1919-1978; 1937-1978; Series 4; 2 Linear Feet
  - London, Report on British Unemployment for President Hoover [1/2], 1929-1931; Series 4 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - London, Report on British Unemployment for President Hoover [2/2], 1931; Series 4 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - United States Social Security Board--Bureau of Research and Statistics--"Prices in Recession and Recovery", 1936; Series 4 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - United States Social Security Board, circa 1937-1942; Series 4 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - United States Social Security Board--"Selected Current Statistics" Desk Bulletin, 04/1937; Series 4 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - United States Social Security Board--"Financing the Act," Falk copy, Summer 1942; Series 4 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - United States Department of State--Board of Economic Warfare and Division on Postwar Planning, 1941-1945; Series 4 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - United States Department of State--Board of Economic Warfare and Division on Postwar Planning, 1944; Series 4 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - United States Department of State--Bretton Woods Conference, 1944; Series 4 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - United States Department of State--Austria, 1945 and undated; Series 4 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - United States Department of State--Austria--Photographs [1/2], circa 1947; Series 4 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - United States Department of State--Austria--Photographs (includes Czechoslovakia) [2/2], 1947; Series 4 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - United States Department of State--Austria--Negatives, circa 1947; Series 4 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - United States Department of State--German Austrian Division, 1949; Series 4 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - United States Department of State--German Office, 1951-1959; Series 4 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - United States Department of State--German Office--Berlin--Souvenirs and Brochures, 1955 and undated; Series 4 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - United States Department of State--German Office--Scrapbook, "Ferienaktion Mit Jugendlichen Aus Der Sowjetzone auf Burg Feuerstein", 1955-1956; Series 4 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - United States Department of State--German Office--Dedication of Congress Hall, Berlin, 10/03/1956-10/05/1957; Series 4 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - United States Department of State--Office of Intelligence and Research--Laying of Cornerstone for Klinikum Hospital, Berlin, and Dedication, 10/21/1959-10/30/1968; Series 4 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - United States Department of State--Office of Intelligence and Research, 1960-1962; Series 4 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - United States Department of State--Office of Intelligence and Research--Africa, 1960-1963; Series 4 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - United States Department of State--Office of Intelligence and Research--Asia, 1960; Series 4 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Teaching--Duke University, 12/05/1962-12/12/1962; Series 4 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Lecture Tour, 1962; Series 4 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Center for Strategic Studies, Georgetown University, 1964-1967 and undated; Series 4 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Center for Strategic Studies, Georgetown University--"Dominican Action 1965: Intervention or Cooperation", 06/20/1966-09/20/1966; Series 4 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Center for Strategic Studies, Georgetown University--"Congo and the United Nations"--Draft [1/2], 09/30/1966; Series 4 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Center for Strategic Studies, Georgetown University--"Congo and the United Nations"--Draft [2/2], 10/11/1966; Series 4 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Writing and Research at Hoover Institute, California, 1967-1968; Series 4 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Consultant for United States Department of State, 1970-circa 1978; Series 4 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Consulting Trip to Berlin, September 1977, for United States Department of State, 02/16/1977-11/07/1977; Series 4 (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Travel, 1965-1990; 1965-1985; Series 5; 1 Linear Feet
  This series contains material relevant to Eleanor Lansing Dulles' travel abroad, particularly to Germany and Austria. The material represents trips taken by Dulles not as an official paid representative of the United States Government, but as an honored guest for important state ceremonies and celebrations. The series includes invitations, itineraries, programs, photographs, correspondence, clippings, and speeches. The material dates between 1965 and 1990, with the bulk of the material dating between 1965 and 1985.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Austria, Guest of Austrian Government, 05/1965; Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Bonn--Death of Konrad Adenauer, 04/20/1967; Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Berlin and Bonn, 1972, 09/13/1972-09/14/1972; Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Berlin--Celebration of End of Blockade, 05/12/1974; Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Austria--20th Anniversary of State Treaty, 05/19/1975; Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Austria--25th Anniversary of the Signing of the Austrian State Treaty, 05/15/1980-05/16/1980; Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Berlin, 1983, Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - German-American Friendship Week, 04/29/1985-05/11/1985, Receipt of Clay Medal and Honorary Professorship, 04/12/1985-06/10/1985; Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Berlin--Reconstruction and Rededication of Congress Hall, Berlin, 11/1982-09/1987; Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Berlin--Free University 40th Anniversary Celebration, 07/25/1988-12/16/1988; Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Germany--Celebration of 95th Birthday, 05/30/1990-08/05/1990; Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 12)
- Family History and Legacy, 1867-1991; 1935-1990; Series 6; 1.25 Linear Feet
  Series 6 is comprised of material related to the history and legacy of the Dulles family. Materials include genealogical information about the Dulles family, photographs, clippings, correspondence and memoranda, an autograph album, manuscripts, publications, programs, brochures, and an interview transcription. The materials date between 1867 and 1991, with the majority of the material dating between 1935 and 1990. Documents in this series were created by, or are about, individual members of the family including Allen Macy Dulles, Allen Welsh Dulles, Avery Dulles, Edith Foster Dulles, Janet Foster Dulles, John Foster Dulles, John W. Foster, and Robert Lansing. The series also contains material pertaining to the legacy of members of the Dulles family, including criticism of biographies of the Dulles family, and information about the establishment of the John Foster Dulles Program for the Study of Leadership in Foreign Affairs at Princeton University, and the John Foster and Janet Dulles Rooms at the University of Texas, Austin.
  Of particular note is a memoir written by Eleanor Lansing Dulles' mother, Edith Foster Dulles, for Eleanor's daughter, Ann, in 1939. The memoir is about Edith Foster Dulles' childhood experiences living in Mexico from 1873 to 1880, while her father, John W. Foster, served as the United States Minister to Mexico.
  Arrangement is alphabetical by family member's name, with general information about the Dulles family grouped at the beginning of the series.
  - Family History and Legacy, 1953-1987; Series 6 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Family History and Legacy--Album and Correspondence, 1867-1891; Series 6 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Family History and Legacy--Allen Dulles, 1933-1975; Series 6 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Family History and Legacy--Avery Dulles, 09/03/1988-10/02/1988; Series 6 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Family History and Legacy--Correspondence--Richard H. Immerman, 09/06/1979-11/08/1979; Series 6 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Family History and Legacy--Criticism of Leonard Mosely's Biography of Dulles Family, 02/23/1978-05/04/1978; Series 6 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Family History and Legacy--Edith Foster Dulles, 1918-1941 and undated; Series 6 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Family History and Legacy--Edith Foster Dulles--"Memoirs of Time Spent in Mexico 1873-1880", 06/14/1939; Series 6 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Family History and Legacy--Janet Foster Dulles, 1962-1978; Series 6 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Family History and Legacy--John Foster Dulles, 1935-1985; Series 6 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Family History and Legacy--John Foster Dulles--About, 1944-1987 and undated; Series 6 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Family History and Legacy--John Foster Dulles Program for the Study of Leadership in Foreign Affairs, Princeton University--Correspondence, 09/19/1986-12/19/1990; Series 6 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Family History and Legacy--John Foster Dulles Program for the Study of Leadership in Foreign Affairs, Princeton University, 1988-1991; Series 6 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Family History and Legacy--John Foster Dulles--Sino-American Crises in the 1950s--Interview and Clippings, 1955-1980; Series 6 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Family History and Legacy--John W. Foster, 1887-1975; Series 6 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Family History and Legacy--Robert Lansing, 1919-1961; Series 6 (Box 25, Folder 4)